Meghana Venkata (1) Featured

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Core Java, Java design patterns, JSP, HTML, JavaScript, Spring MVC, Hibernate, GIT, Maven



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: under graduation [BTech Ece]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Software Testing, Application Support, Technical Support, Network Administration, JSP, HTML, JavaScript, Spring

MVC, Hibernate, GIT, Eclipse, Tortoise SVN

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Result-oriented Professional with over 2.7 years of experience in Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Software Testing, Application Support, Technical Support, Network Administration Java, JSP, HTML, JavaScript, Spring MVC, Spring boot, Microservices, Hibernate, GIT, Maven, Eclipse, Tortoise SVN.

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. as Software Developer Jun 2018 to Till Date

Juli 2016 to Till Date

Requirement gathering, analysis of new requirement, effort estimation.

As a software developer, responsible for software development, which includes new functional requirement, process improvement and change requirements as well.

Client facing role with interactions directly with the client to know their exact requirements and deadlines then discuss the same within team and implement the solution accordingly.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from VNR Vignan Jyothi Institute of Engineering and Technology, Hyderabad in 2018

PG: under graduation (BTech Ece) in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Core Java/ J2EE ,Servlets	
JSP, HTML, JavaScript	
Spring MVC , Hibernate, Collection(Basic	
Unix Shell Script, Cronjobs	
DB2	
Eclipse	
Tortoise SVN, GIT	
Apache Tomcat	
WebSphere Application Server	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
ENGLISH				
HINDI				
TELUGU				

Projects

Project Title: Taxation Information Network (TIN) Client: National Securities Depository Ltd. (NSDL)

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Tax Information Network (TIN) is a system for collecting, processing and accounting of direct taxes using Information Technology. It is an initiative taken by Income Tax Department (ITD). TIN has been established by NSDL. Users can file their TDS/TCS online with the help of this websites. Also users can register themselves for Online pan Cards.

Affirmative Action

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization